<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>OpenConstruction — Updates</title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/</link>
    <description>Newest datasets and models from OpenConstruction</description>
    <language>en-US</language>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Model: TLSynth: A Novel Blender Add-On for Real-Time Point Cloud Generation from 3D Models]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/models.html</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">models:TLSynth:2025-11-11</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[Point clouds are a crucial element in the process of scanning and reconstructing 3D environments, such as buildings or heritage sites. They allow for the creation of 3D models that can be used in a wide range of applications. In some cases, however, only the 3D model of an environment is available, and it is necessary to obtain point clouds with the same characteristics as those captured by a laser scanner. For instance, point clouds may be required for surveys, performance optimization, site scan planning, or validation of point cloud processing algorithms. This paper presents a new terrestrial laser scanner (TLS) simulator, designed as a Blender add-on, that produces synthetic point clouds from 3D models in real time. The simulator allows users to adjust a set of parameters to replicate real-world scanning conditions, such as noise generation, ensuring the synthetic point clouds closely mirror those produced by actual laser scanners. The target meshes may be derived from either a real-world scan or 3D designs created using design software. By replicating the spatial distributions and attributes of real laser scanner outputs and supporting real-time generation, the simulator serves as a valuable tool for scan planning and the development of synthetic point cloud repositories, advancing research and practical applications in 3D computer vision.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Dataset: CODE-ACCORD: Automated Compliance Checks for Construction, Renovation or Demolition Works (ACCORD)]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/datasets/detail.html?id=code-accord</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">datasets:code-accord:2025-11-10</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[New dataset added to OpenConstruction.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Dataset: CubiCasa5K: A Dataset and an Improved Multi-Task Model for Floorplan Image Analysis]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/datasets/detail.html?id=cubicasa5k</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">datasets:cubicasa5k:2025-11-10</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[New dataset added to OpenConstruction.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Dataset: Concrete crack dataset for beam and column]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/datasets/detail.html?id=concrete-crack-lab</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">datasets:concrete-crack-lab:2025-11-7</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[New dataset added to OpenConstruction.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Dataset: BIMNet: Dataset and benchmark for as-built BIM reconstruction from real-world point cloud]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/datasets/detail.html?id=BIMNet</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">datasets:BIMNet:2025-11-6</guid>
    <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[New dataset added to OpenConstruction.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Dataset: Point Cloud Dataset for Piping Systems]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/datasets/detail.html?id=BIM_updating</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">datasets:BIM_updating:2025-11-4</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[New dataset added to OpenConstruction.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Dataset: Pictor-v3]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/datasets/detail.html?id=pictor-ppe</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">datasets:pictor-ppe:2025-11-4</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[New dataset added to OpenConstruction.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Dataset: DoriaNET: A visual dataset for post-disaster building damage assessment]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/datasets/detail.html?id=DoriaNET</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">datasets:DoriaNET:2025-11-4</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[New dataset added to OpenConstruction.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Model: Semi-automated localised updating for as-built BIM of piping systems using point cloud data]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/models.html</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">models:BIM_updating:2025-11-4</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[As-designed building information models (BIM) often diverge from as-built conditions, limiting their reliability during the operation and maintenance (O&M). Current research focuses on change detection but lacks a systematic workflow for reliable updates, especially for piping systems with frequent changes and complex geometries. The paper addresses how to establish a semi-automated, end-to-end workflow for localised updating as-designed BIM of piping systems from point cloud data. The workflow applies PointNet++ for segmentation, followed by iterative closest point, random sample consensus, and region-growing for geometry extraction. The proposed BIM updating taxonomy and dedicated pre-judgment updating requirements (PUR) and spatial and topological relationships up-dating (STRU) algorithms identify update requirements and automate parametric updates. Validation through case studies demonstrates the workflow's ability to accurately perform localised updates, reducing the manual workload by approximately 70 %. This practical, scalable solution strengthens O&M by maintaining accurate as-built models and inspires future automated BIM updating research.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Model: Deep learning for post-hurricane aerial damage assessment of buildings]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/models.html</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">models:DoriaNET:2025-11-4</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[This study aims to improve post-disaster preliminary damage assessment (PDA) using artificial intelligence (AI) and unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV) imagery. In particular, a stacked convolutional neural network (CNN) architecture is introduced and trained on an in-house visual dataset from Hurricane Dorian. To account for the ordinality of damage level classes, the cross-entropy classification loss function is replaced with the square of earth mover's distance (EMD2) loss. The trained model achieves 65.6% building localization precision and 61% (90% considering ±1 class deviation from ground-truth) classification accuracy. It also exhibits a positive accuracy–confidence correlation, which is valuable for model assessment in situations where ground-truth information is not readily available. Finally, the outcome of damage assessment is compared with the literature by examining the relationship between building size and number of stories, and severity of induced disaster damage.]]></description>
  </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
