<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>OpenConstruction — Updates</title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/</link>
    <description>Newest datasets and models from OpenConstruction</description>
    <language>en-US</language>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Model: xView2 Baseline: Localization and Classification Models for Building Damage Assessment]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/models.html</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">models:xView2_baseline:2026-01-30</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[New model added to OpenConstruction.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Dataset: xBD: A Dataset for Assessing Building Damage from Satellite Imagery]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/datasets/detail.html?id=xBD</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">datasets:xBD:2026-01-29</guid>
    <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[New dataset added to OpenConstruction.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Dataset: OLBDA: Object-Level Building Damage Assessment Dataset]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/datasets/detail.html?id=BDAChat</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">datasets:BDAChat:2026-01-20</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[New dataset added to OpenConstruction.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Model: BDAChat: Temporal Vision-Language Model for Object-Level Building Damage Assessment]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/models.html</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">models:BDAChat:2026-01-20</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[The rapid assessment of constructed facilities after extreme events is a knowledge-intensive task critical for effective emergency management. However, methodologies for automated, object-level damage assessment at scale remain underdeveloped, often lacking fine-grained interpretability or scalability. This paper introduces a framework that integrates instance segmentation with temporal Vision Language Model (VLM), which is empowered with visual damage reasoning capabilities through fine-tuning on domain-specific knowledge, for the automated and interpretable assessment of structural assets from satellite imagery. Our three-stage approach synergizes: high-precision segmentation via a modified Segment Anything Model (SAM); spatiotemporal data pairing to isolate asset-specific changes; and BDAChat, the first temporal VLM fine-tuned for object-level damage assessment. Unlike traditional black-box models, BDAChat provides both high-accuracy damage classification and causal interpretations, serving as an intelligent damage inference system. The framework’s effectiveness and scalability are validated through the Lahaina wildfire and hurricane Ian case study. This modular framework automates and accelerates the object-level building damage assessment process, demonstrating significant potential for real-time building damage evaluation and resilient infrastructure planning. The code and dataset are available at https://github.com/WangYong921/BDAChat.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Dataset: Construction classification system database]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/datasets/detail.html?id=CCS-ResourceUse</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">datasets:CCS-ResourceUse:2026-01-17</guid>
    <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[New dataset added to OpenConstruction.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Dataset: Large-Scale Construction Time–Cost Trade-off Dataset]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/datasets/detail.html?id=RAOA-DTCTP</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">datasets:RAOA-DTCTP:2026-01-17</guid>
    <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[New dataset added to OpenConstruction.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Model: Self-supervised learning for multi-label sewer defect classification]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/models.html</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">models:MultiLabel_SewerDefect_SSL:2026-01-17</guid>
    <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[Automated sewer defect detection has advanced through deep learning, particularly supervised methods using CCTV images, but based on large annotated datasets. This paper proposes a semi-supervised learning (SSL) approach to reduce labeling demands. The method comprises self-supervised pre-training on unlabeled images using SwAV (Swapping Assignments between multiple Views) followed by fine-tuning for multi-label classification. Experiments on the Sewer-ML dataset demonstrate that the SSL approach, trained on only 35k labeled images, achieves an F1-score of 69.11%, and F2CIW of 54.22%, surpassing the fully supervised baseline trained from scratch on 1.04 million images. Increasing the unlabeled pre-training data further enhances performance, while ImageNet initialization consistently outperforms training from scratch. Self-supervised learning also helps mitigate the effects of mislabeled data, which is observed to be present even in the Sewer-ML ground truth. Overall, self-supervised learning provides an accurate, scalable, and cost-effective alternative to fully supervised approaches, particularly in data-scarce or imperfectly labeled scenarios.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Dataset: IFC-based BIM Geometry]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/datasets/detail.html?id=IFCNet</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">datasets:IFCNet:2026-01-11</guid>
    <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[New dataset added to OpenConstruction.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Dataset: Construction Time–Cost Trade-off Dataset]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/datasets/detail.html?id=DTCTP</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">datasets:DTCTP:2026-01-11</guid>
    <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[New dataset added to OpenConstruction.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Model: SpaRSE-BIM: Classification of IFC-based geometry via sparse convolutional neural networks]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/models.html</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">models:SpaRSE-BIM:2026-01-11</guid>
    <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[Information exchange between Building Information Modeling (BIM) tools is challenging, since many applications use their own native data formats. The Industry Foundation Classes (IFC) schema, an open data exchange format for BIM, does not capture the full semantic meaning needed for direct use by different BIM tools and can be prone to information loss due to reduction, simplification, translation and interpretation of the data. Current practice often treats the imported model as a reference and requires a user to remodel the building using the respective application’s native elements. Many BIM object properties are defined by its classification. Inconsistencies in the mapping between native BIM elements and IFC, e.g. due to unsupported export functionality or manual error, can lead to problems when using the model in a downstream application. Recent works demonstrate that neural networks offer a promising possibility to alleviate this issue via classification of the objects contained in a BIM model and suggesting those corrections to the user. However, the computational overhead of these deep learning models, either due to necessary pre-processing of the data or runtime performance of the model, makes it difficult for them to be used in plug-ins or middleware for BIM tools. This work proposes SpaRSE-BIM, a neural network model based on sparse convolutions for the classification of IFC-based geometry and semantic enrichment of BIM models. Experiments are performed on two IFC entity classification benchmark datasets. The results demonstrate that SpaRSE-BIM is significantly more efficient at inference time compared to previous approaches, while maintaining state-of-the-art accuracy. Further experiments explore the applicability of IFC entity classification datasets to the domain of Scan-to-BIM. It can be shown that the feature space of SpaRSE-BIM learns to discern objects in a semantically meaningful way, even in cases where fine-grained subtype information for IFC objects is not available during training.]]></description>
  </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
