<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>OpenConstruction — Updates</title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/</link>
    <description>Newest datasets and models from OpenConstruction</description>
    <language>en-US</language>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Model: VoxCity: Grid-based semantic 3D city model generation, and urban environment simulation]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/models.html</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">models:VoxCity:2026-01-07</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[Three-dimensional urban environment simulation is a powerful tool for informed urban planning. However, the intensive manual effort required to prepare input 3D city models has hindered its widespread adoption. To address this challenge, we present VoxCity, an open-source Python package that provides a one-stop solution for grid-based 3D city model generation and urban environment simulation for cities worldwide. VoxCity’s ‘generator’ subpackage automatically downloads building heights, tree canopy heights, land cover, and terrain elevation within a specified target area, and voxelizes buildings, trees, land cover, and terrain to generate an integrated voxel city model. The ‘simulator’ subpackage enables users to conduct environmental simulations, including solar radiation and view index analyses. Users can export the generated models using several file formats compatible with external software, such as ENVI-met (INX), Blender, and Rhino (OBJ). We generated 3D city models for eight global cities, and demonstrated the calculation of solar irradiance, sky view index, and green view index. We also showcased microclimate simulation and 3D rendering visualization through ENVI-met and Rhino, respectively, through the file export function. Additionally, we reviewed openly available geospatial data to create guidelines to help users choose appropriate data sources depending on their target areas and purposes. VoxCity can significantly reduce the effort and time required for 3D city model preparation and promote the utilization of urban environment simulations. This contributes to more informed urban and architectural design that considers environmental impacts, and in turn, fosters sustainable and livable cities. VoxCity is released openly at https://github.com/kunifujiwara/VoxCity]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Dataset: AEC Objects in IFC-based BIM Dataset]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/datasets/detail.html?id=AEC_Objects_in_IFC-based_BIM</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">datasets:AEC_Objects_in_IFC-based_BIM:2025-12-30</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[New dataset added to OpenConstruction.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Dataset: Indoor FireRescue Rada (IFR) dataset]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/datasets/detail.html?id=IFR_Dataset</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">datasets:IFR_Dataset:2025-12-29</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[New dataset added to OpenConstruction.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Model: DUSt3R: Geometric 3D Vision Made Easy]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/models.html</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">models:DUSt3R:2025-12-09</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[Multi-view stereo reconstruction (MVS) in the wild requires to first estimate the camera parameters e.g. intrinsic and extrinsic parameters. These are usually tedious and cumbersome to obtain, yet they are mandatory to triangulate corresponding pixels in 3D space, which is the core of all best performing MVS algorithms. In this work, we take an opposite stance and introduce DUSt3R, a radically novel paradigm for Dense and Unconstrained Stereo 3D Reconstruction of arbitrary image collections, i.e. operating without prior information about camera calibration nor viewpoint poses. We cast the pairwise reconstruction problem as a regression of pointmaps, relaxing the hard constraints of usual projective camera models. We show that this formulation smoothly unifies the monocular and binocular reconstruction cases. In the case where more than two images are provided, we further propose a simple yet effective global alignment strategy that expresses all pairwise pointmaps in a common reference frame. We base our network architecture on standard Transformer encoders and decoders, allowing us to leverage powerful pretrained models. Our formulation directly provides a 3D model of the scene as well as depth information, but interestingly, we can seamlessly recover from it, pixel matches, relative and absolute camera. Exhaustive experiments on all these tasks showcase that the proposed DUSt3R can unify various 3D vision tasks and set new SoTAs on monocular/multi-view depth estimation as well as relative pose estimation. In summary, DUSt3R makes many geometric 3D vision tasks easy.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Model: EnergyPlus-MCP: A model-context-protocol server for AI-driven building energy modeling]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/models.html</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">models:EnergyPlus-MCP:2025-12-08</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[Traditional building energy modeling with the EnergyPlus building performance simulation engine requires domain expertise, programming skills, and intensive manual efforts limiting its effective adoption. This paper introduces EnergyPlus-MCP, the first open-source Model Context Protocol (MCP) server specifically designed for EnergyPlus simulation workflows, establishing a new foundational infrastructure for AI-driven building energy modeling. The MCP server implements a layered architecture with 35 specialized tools spanning model management, editing and analysis, HVAC and other systems configuration inspection, and simulation execution, enabling Large Language Models to interact with EnergyPlus through conversational interfaces. The server addresses critical workflow barriers by automating model validation, streamlining energy efficiency measures modification, and providing intelligent output management with interactive visualization. Through practical demonstrations using a multi-zone building retrofit analysis, we show how the EnergyPlus-MCP server significantly reduces manual efforts while maintaining full simulation rigor. By providing accessible natural language interfaces to sophisticated building energy analysis, this approach enables scalable deployment of simulation expertise across public and private organizations, educational institutions, and research teams, fundamentally transforming traditional building energy modeling practices.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Model: A KG-LLM-Enabled Inspection Work Packaging Approach in Module Prefabrication]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/models.html</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">models:KG-LLM-inspection-work-packaging:2025-12-05</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[Quality inspection during the production of modular construction (MC) is critical to the success of MC projects because defects such as geometric errors can severely impact installation. Therefore, the effective organization and management of quality inspection is essential. Although work packaging has proven to be an effective method for project planning, automatically and accurately generating inspection work packages remains a challenge, particularly in mass production. To this end, this study aims to develop a knowledge graph-large language model (KG-LLM)-enabled inspection work packaging approach in MC production. First, a KG is constructed to represent inspection knowledge, encompassing inspection tasks, target MC products, inspectors, inspection tools, inspection frequencies, and corresponding production processes, which can enrich LLM in product2inspection mapping and can help identify features of inspection tasks for inspection2package clustering. Second, a prompt-based product2inspection mapping approach leveraging LLM is developed. Next, inspection2package clustering is completed through hierarchical agglomerative clustering, with parameters optimized by particle swarm optimization (PSO). Finally, the effectiveness of the proposed approach is validated through controlled experiments on an MC case project. This study demonstrates how leveraging KG and LLMs can enhance collaboration in quality inspection during module prefabrication and highlights the potential of LLMs in the construction domain.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Dataset: GlobalBuildingAtlas]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/datasets/detail.html?id=GlobalBuildingAtlas</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">datasets:GlobalBuildingAtlas:2025-12-4</guid>
    <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[New dataset added to OpenConstruction.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Dataset: Global dataset of critical infrastructure]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/datasets/detail.html?id=CISI</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">datasets:CISI:2025-11-28</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[New dataset added to OpenConstruction.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Dataset: VideoCAD: Learning Long-Horizon 3D CAD UI Interactions from Video]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/datasets/detail.html?id=VideoCAD</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">datasets:VideoCAD:2025-11-26</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[New dataset added to OpenConstruction.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Dataset: Construction Management Systems (CMS) Domain Corpora]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/datasets/detail.html?id=cms-domain-corpora</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">datasets:cms-domain-corpora:2025-11-26</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[New dataset added to OpenConstruction.]]></description>
  </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
