<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>OpenConstruction — Updates</title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/</link>
    <description>Newest datasets and models from OpenConstruction</description>
    <language>en-US</language>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Model: xView2 Baseline: Localization and Classification Models for Building Damage Assessment]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/models.html</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">models:xView2_baseline:2026-01-30</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[We present xBD, a new, large-scale dataset for the advancement of change detection and building damage assessment for humanitarian assistance and disaster recovery research. Natural disaster response requires an accurate understanding of damaged buildings in an affected region. Current response strategies require in-person damage assessments within 24-48 hours of a disaster. Massive potential exists for using aerial imagery combined with computer vision algorithms to assess damage and reduce the potential danger to human life. In collaboration with multiple disaster response agencies, xBD provides pre- and post-event satellite imagery across a variety of disaster events with building polygons, ordinal labels of damage level, and corresponding satellite metadata. Furthermore, the dataset contains bounding boxes and labels for environmental factors such as fire, water, and smoke. xBD is the largest building damage assessment dataset to date, containing 850,736 building annotations across 45,362 km	extsuperscript{2} of imagery.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Model: Domain-adaptive instance segmentation for far-field object monitoring using SAM-based weak supervision and noisy student self-training]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/models.html</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">models:Weak_and_Self-supervision_model:2026-01-30</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[Automating construction site monitoring through deep learning–based segmentation presents challenges due to the high cost of pixel-wise annotations. This paper introduces a weakly and self-supervised learning framework that enhances segmentation accuracy while reducing annotation burden. Human-annotated bounding-box ground truth is used as prompts for the Segment Anything Model (SAM) to generate high-quality polygon mask labels, which are further refined through self-training. Compared to fully supervised learning models, the framework integrates Transfer Learning, Pseudo-Label Refinement, and the Noisy Student technique, improving mask mean Average Precision (Mask mAP) by 3–63% across seven target domains and achieving a Mask mAP of 72.27%. The approach also outperforms existing weakly supervised techniques, including BoxSnake and BoxTeacher, by 18% and 25.95%, respectively, and exceeds the performance of point-based methods such as PointWSSIS by 48.78%.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Dataset: xBD: A Dataset for Assessing Building Damage from Satellite Imagery]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/datasets/detail.html?id=xBD</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">datasets:xBD:2026-01-29</guid>
    <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[New dataset added to OpenConstruction.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Dataset: Construction Site Safety Dataset]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/datasets/detail.html?id=Weak_and_Self_supervision</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">datasets:Weak_and_Self_supervision:2026-01-29</guid>
    <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[New dataset added to OpenConstruction.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Dataset: MACO: Material Counting in Construction]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/datasets/detail.html?id=MACO</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">datasets:MACO:2026-01-29</guid>
    <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[New dataset added to OpenConstruction.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Dataset: OLBDA: Object-Level Building Damage Assessment Dataset]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/datasets/detail.html?id=BDAChat</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">datasets:BDAChat:2026-01-20</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[New dataset added to OpenConstruction.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Model: BDAChat: Temporal Vision-Language Model for Object-Level Building Damage Assessment]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/models.html</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">models:BDAChat:2026-01-20</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[The rapid assessment of constructed facilities after extreme events is a knowledge-intensive task critical for effective emergency management. However, methodologies for automated, object-level damage assessment at scale remain underdeveloped, often lacking fine-grained interpretability or scalability. This paper introduces a framework that integrates instance segmentation with temporal Vision Language Model (VLM), which is empowered with visual damage reasoning capabilities through fine-tuning on domain-specific knowledge, for the automated and interpretable assessment of structural assets from satellite imagery. Our three-stage approach synergizes: high-precision segmentation via a modified Segment Anything Model (SAM); spatiotemporal data pairing to isolate asset-specific changes; and BDAChat, the first temporal VLM fine-tuned for object-level damage assessment. Unlike traditional black-box models, BDAChat provides both high-accuracy damage classification and causal interpretations, serving as an intelligent damage inference system. The framework’s effectiveness and scalability are validated through the Lahaina wildfire and hurricane Ian case study. This modular framework automates and accelerates the object-level building damage assessment process, demonstrating significant potential for real-time building damage evaluation and resilient infrastructure planning. The code and dataset are available at https://github.com/WangYong921/BDAChat.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Dataset: Construction classification system database]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/datasets/detail.html?id=CCS-ResourceUse</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">datasets:CCS-ResourceUse:2026-01-17</guid>
    <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[New dataset added to OpenConstruction.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Dataset: Large-Scale Construction Time–Cost Trade-off Dataset]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/datasets/detail.html?id=RAOA-DTCTP</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">datasets:RAOA-DTCTP:2026-01-17</guid>
    <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[New dataset added to OpenConstruction.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Model: Self-supervised learning for multi-label sewer defect classification]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/models.html</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">models:MultiLabel_SewerDefect_SSL:2026-01-17</guid>
    <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[Automated sewer defect detection has advanced through deep learning, particularly supervised methods using CCTV images, but based on large annotated datasets. This paper proposes a semi-supervised learning (SSL) approach to reduce labeling demands. The method comprises self-supervised pre-training on unlabeled images using SwAV (Swapping Assignments between multiple Views) followed by fine-tuning for multi-label classification. Experiments on the Sewer-ML dataset demonstrate that the SSL approach, trained on only 35k labeled images, achieves an F1-score of 69.11%, and F2CIW of 54.22%, surpassing the fully supervised baseline trained from scratch on 1.04 million images. Increasing the unlabeled pre-training data further enhances performance, while ImageNet initialization consistently outperforms training from scratch. Self-supervised learning also helps mitigate the effects of mislabeled data, which is observed to be present even in the Sewer-ML ground truth. Overall, self-supervised learning provides an accurate, scalable, and cost-effective alternative to fully supervised approaches, particularly in data-scarce or imperfectly labeled scenarios.]]></description>
  </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
