<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>OpenConstruction — Updates</title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/</link>
    <description>Newest datasets and models from OpenConstruction</description>
    <language>en-US</language>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Dataset: CODE-ACCORD: Automated Compliance Checks for Construction, Renovation or Demolition Works (ACCORD)]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/datasets/detail.html?id=code-accord</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">datasets:code-accord:2025-11-11</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[New dataset added to OpenConstruction.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Dataset: Concrete crack dataset for beam and column]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/datasets/detail.html?id=concrete-crack-lab</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">datasets:concrete-crack-lab:2025-11-7</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[New dataset added to OpenConstruction.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Dataset: BIMNet: Dataset and benchmark for as-built BIM reconstruction from real-world point cloud]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/datasets/detail.html?id=BIMNet</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">datasets:BIMNet:2025-11-6</guid>
    <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[New dataset added to OpenConstruction.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Dataset: Point Cloud Dataset for Piping Systems]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/datasets/detail.html?id=BIM_updating</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">datasets:BIM_updating:2025-11-4</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[New dataset added to OpenConstruction.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Dataset: Pictor-v3]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/datasets/detail.html?id=pictor-ppe</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">datasets:pictor-ppe:2025-11-4</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[New dataset added to OpenConstruction.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Dataset: DoriaNET: A visual dataset for post-disaster building damage assessment]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/datasets/detail.html?id=DoriaNET</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">datasets:DoriaNET:2025-11-4</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[New dataset added to OpenConstruction.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Model: Semi-automated localised updating for as-built BIM of piping systems using point cloud data]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/models.html</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">models:BIM_updating:2025-11-4</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[As-designed building information models (BIM) often diverge from as-built conditions, limiting their reliability during the operation and maintenance (O&M). Current research focuses on change detection but lacks a systematic workflow for reliable updates, especially for piping systems with frequent changes and complex geometries. The paper addresses how to establish a semi-automated, end-to-end workflow for localised updating as-designed BIM of piping systems from point cloud data. The workflow applies PointNet++ for segmentation, followed by iterative closest point, random sample consensus, and region-growing for geometry extraction. The proposed BIM updating taxonomy and dedicated pre-judgment updating requirements (PUR) and spatial and topological relationships up-dating (STRU) algorithms identify update requirements and automate parametric updates. Validation through case studies demonstrates the workflow's ability to accurately perform localised updates, reducing the manual workload by approximately 70 %. This practical, scalable solution strengthens O&M by maintaining accurate as-built models and inspires future automated BIM updating research.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Model: Deep learning for post-hurricane aerial damage assessment of buildings]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/models.html</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">models:DoriaNET:2025-11-4</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[This study aims to improve post-disaster preliminary damage assessment (PDA) using artificial intelligence (AI) and unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV) imagery. In particular, a stacked convolutional neural network (CNN) architecture is introduced and trained on an in-house visual dataset from Hurricane Dorian. To account for the ordinality of damage level classes, the cross-entropy classification loss function is replaced with the square of earth mover's distance (EMD2) loss. The trained model achieves 65.6% building localization precision and 61% (90% considering ±1 class deviation from ground-truth) classification accuracy. It also exhibits a positive accuracy–confidence correlation, which is valuable for model assessment in situations where ground-truth information is not readily available. Finally, the outcome of damage assessment is compared with the literature by examining the relationship between building size and number of stories, and severity of induced disaster damage.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Dataset: BMKG: Bridge Maintenance Knowledge Graph]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/datasets/detail.html?id=BMKG</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">datasets:BMKG:2025-11-3</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[New dataset added to OpenConstruction.]]></description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Model: Knowledge graph-driven bridge maintenance decision-making via integrating large language models and chain-of-thought reasoning]]></title>
    <link>https://www.openconstruction.org/models.html</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">models:BMKG-DCoT:2025-11-03</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[Bridge maintenance knowledge graphs (BMKGs) contain rich historical records of defects and corresponding maintenance actions, yet few studies exploit this data to guide decisions for new defects. Traditional case-based reasoning (CBR) methods can surface similar historical cases but suffer from high retrieval costs and struggle with ambiguous scenarios. To address these limitations, this paper introduces BMKG-DCoT, which integrates large language models (LLMs) with chain-of-thought (CoT) reasoning to mimic maintenance expert decision workflows. BMKG-DCoT follows a three-phase iterative process—Inference-Planning (formulating reasoning steps and retrieval plans), Interaction-Decision (targeted data extraction from the BMKG), and Observation-Judgment (evaluating and refining inferences). On some standard and ambiguous maintenance queries, BMKG-DCoT achieves F1 scores of 0.9529 and 0.9130, respectively, outperforming baselines. Explainability analyses further confirm that its reasoning paths are transparent and interpretable, underscoring its promise as an AI-driven decision-support tool for bridge maintenance.]]></description>
  </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
